### Contact

Room 105, JVR Residence, Karunya Nagar 641114 ronnietbaby1998@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ronnietbaby (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Ethical Hacking
Cyber Security
Application Security

### Languages

Hindi (Full Professional)

Malayalam (Professional Working)

English (Full Professional)

### Certifications

Workshop on Block Chain Technology – Global Health

Practical Ethical Hacking - The Complete Course

Search Engine Optimisation

Penetration Testing and Ethical Hacking

Information Security :Context and Introduction

### Honors-Awards

Interhouse Quiz Winners

Severe Bug Found-Violation Of secure design principles

Microsoft Security Hall Of Fame

Second Prize in Mock Interview

First Prize in Group Discussion

### **Publications**

**Best Image Optimization Tool** 

Comparative Analysis Of Subdomain Enumeration Tools And Static Code Analysis

Magnum Opus Of Phishing Techniques

## Ronnie Joseph

Security Enthusiast | Microsoft Student Partner Bengaluru

### Summary

Ronnie T Baby is at present a senior student in Karunya University pursuing B Tech. in Computer Science and Engineering. His area of interest includes Application security, web security and has been actively contributing to the security of different organizations.

He has been listed and rewarded in several security HOF viz. Google Hall of Fame, Oracle, Sony, Microsoft, Facebook whitehat List, United Nations, Apple etc.

He loves to "break the code" and believes to help increase the security of online services through his skills. He has been acknowledged by several worldwide companies for responsible security disclosures. He has been featured in several online news media outlets for a bug, found in IRCTC e-Ticketing Site.

He was also selected as one among ~50 students from Asia Pacific region to an invite-only security conference and live hacking event in Singapore organised by Facebook and Google.

He is a native of Kerala, India and completed his schooling from Madhya Pradesh.

Connect with him on LinkedIn to know more about him.

### Experience

Microsoft
Microsoft Student Partner
September 2019 - Present (1 year)
Coimbatore Area, India

MSP for KITS, Coimbatore

# IDN Attacks Jira Instance Data Leak

Independent Cyber Security Researcher Cyber Security Researcher September 2016 - Present (4 years)

Finding vulnerabilities in open programs and reporting them to the concerned authorities.

### Cybrary

Teaching Assistant
October 2019 - March 2020 (6 months)

Giving back to the security community.

### GeekSlider

Founder

April 2017 - September 2018 (1 year 6 months)

Tech Blog Sharing Tips and tricks. https://geekslider.com Now SOLD to College Alumni.

#### Internshala

Internshala Student Partner September 2017 - March 2018 (7 months) India

Money-Wizards

Ambassador

October 2017 - December 2017 (3 months)

Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu, India

Organised Youth Money Olympiad in Karunya Institute of Technology and Sciences

Computer Technology Center, Karunya University Infrastructure Engineer Trainee August 2017 - October 2017 (3 months)

Learning about networks and how to secure them from attacks.

CTC or Computer Technology Center is the place which controls all the technical and network problems of the entire Karunya Network which is amongst South India's biggest WiFi networks. It is headed by experienced HOD Mr. Vinodh Ewards.

CashKaro.com
Marketing Intern
June 2017 - July 2017 (2 months)

### Work From Home

Worked as the marketing intern for popular coupon site Cashkaro.com helping them with SEO optimization, SEM and social media marketing.

### Education

Karunya University

Bachelor of Technology (BTech), Computer science and engineering · (2016 - 2020)

Delhi Public School, Vijaipur Senior Secondary , PCM · (2002 - 2016)